Lee AllenDigital product leader

Summary

Combining front end development expertise, strong design background, and excellent communication skills, I lead teams to create user-centered, engaging, performant web and mobile products. I've helped companies large and small including: Allstate Insurance, Discover Financial Services, Ford Motor Company, Motorola Mobility, and PIMCO.

Experience

PogoTec

Newport Beach, CA (2017-present)

Director of Digital Design & Development

I wear many hats including: UX Designer, UX Engineer, Project Manager, and office IT to keep the Digital Marketing & eCommerce team user-focused and successful.

- Identify resource gaps, create hiring documentation, and build team of UX Designers, UI
 Designers, Design Researchers, and UX Engineers to take all web work in-house from
 agencies, saving the company over \$400k in the first year
- Create, implement, and run iterative design and development workflow for web team to maintain focus through constantly changing demands and tight deadlines
- Choose, setup, create documentation for, and manage all internal tools to facilitate collaboration between a mix of in-office and remote workers
- Create and maintain web product roadmap including: combining multiple micro-sites, launching eCommerce, and preparing for international expansion
- · Setup payment, fulfillment, and reverse logistics to launch the company's first product
- Choose, setup, and manage all third-party website services to provide business with cost-effective analytics for an early-stage startup
- Manage all A/B testing including a test that increased conversions by 400%
- Execute hands-on work when needed including: creating documentation (sitemaps, user flows, specs, PRDs) and developing web functionality

Motorola Mobility

Chicago, IL (2014-2016)

Principal UX Engineering Manager

My team was responsible for high-fidelity (web and mobile app) prototyping, complex web A/B tests, rapid development of new web functionality, and being the liaison between design and development teams.

- Created high-fidelity prototypes using React for web and mobile apps, including
 Moto Maker, the award-winning phone customization platform, and Moto Display, the
 first always-on Android lock screen. This enabled rapid and more useful user testing
 feedback, reduced documentation work for design, and allowed our off-site engineering
 team to more accurately create the design team's intent.
- Created an A/B testing process that brought together Design, Product Management, and IT teams to gather testing needs, prioritize tests, manage deployment, and take action on results, while increasing overall testing velocity
- Developed complex A/B tests with JavaScript resulting in significant business improvements including: cancelling a six-figure product rendering improvement project by proving it would not increase conversions, increasing revenue by abandoning fullbrowser-height content sections, increasing revenue 15% by reordering product page content sections, and doubling revenue by using a different art direction for photography
- Designed, developed, and launched a short-term product comparison page that increased conversions by 50%
- Redeveloped 360° product viewers to decrease their loading time by 500%
- Worked with with Industrial Design, Product Management, and IT to revamp process for creating tens of thousands of product renders for Moto Maker resulting in higher quality, faster production, 80% reduction in web-optimized file size, and lower production costs



Experience Acquity Group, part of Accenture Interactive

Chicago, IL (2008-2014)

I advanced through multiple roles in the Front End Development practice as I helped it grow from 4 to 45 members nationwide.

Senior Front End Development Manager (2012-2014)

I led front end development from early design concepts through deployment, creating Angular web apps, Cordova-based hybrid-mobile apps, and eCommerce websites.

- · Created a tablet app using Angular for a major clothing retailer allowing shoppers to virtually create their outfits, replacing a slow in-person process
- · Led front end on a connected car project for a major American automaker creating responsive web, iOS, and Android apps from the same codebase to remotely control their electric cars, integrating with Adobe Experience Manager for easy content updates
- · Took over mid-project as front end manager on a hybrid mobile app (web, iOS, and Android) for a major regional utility that was weeks behind schedule. I restructured the team and codebase to deliver a solution with 95% code sharing between platforms.
- Led front end team's embrace of modern front end tooling and single-page applications
- · Built strong relationships with clients from initial pitches through product launches
- Mentored multiple junior and senior developers as their Career Advisement Manager
- · Participated in business development pursuits of Fortune 500 companies helping to secure tens of millions of dollars' worth of work

Front End Development Manager (2011–2012)

- · Lead technical architect for eight-figure mobile agency of record account with Fortune 100 financial services firm
- · Managed, architected, and developed multiple mobile web and hybrid iOS/Android Cordova projects including bringing their first tablet app to market

Senior Front End Developer (2008-2011)

- · Built mobile-optimized sites for multiple clients
- Started mobile device testing lab, building it to 75 devices
- Developed infographics-heavy connected car dashboard for top-5 insurance company
- · Developed sites for multiple clients including: world's largest bond trading firm and two Fortune 500 biotech companies

The Vertebrae Group

Marion, IL (2007-2008)

Co-Founder & Partner

- · Designed eCommerce website and Flash application UIs
- · Developed websites using standards-compliant HTML, CSS, and JavaScript while everyone else optimized for IE6

Evolution Multimedia Corporation

Herrin, IL (2002-2007)

Hybrid UI Designer/Developer

- · Designed and developed UIs for websites, Flash, and desktop applications
- Moved company to standards-based front end development
- · Led UI design for a multi-million dollar gaming startup

Education BFA in Communication Design

Southern Illinois University, Carbondale

AWards 2015 Webby Awards

Consumer Electronics Website Honoree for Moto Maker

Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM)

Scrum Alliance

Phi Ro Pi National Tournament

Silver Medal in Impromptu Speaking Silver Medal in Extemporaneous Speaking